A Step Beyond Science Fiction
Heavy Metal is a animation, science fiction,
adventure film directed by Gerald Potterton.
The embodiment of ultimate evil, a glowing orb terrorizes a young girl
with bizarre stories of dark fantasy, eroticism and horror.
Hanover Fiste / Dr. Anrak (voice), played by Rodger Bumpass.
Desk Sergeant / Dan / Den / Robot (voice), played by John Candy.
Katherine (voice), played by Jackie Burroughs.
Lawyer / General (voice), played by Joe Flaherty.
Grimaldi / Co-Pilot / Barbarian (voice), played by Don Francks.
Whore / Queen (voice), played by Marilyn Lightstone.
Heavy Metal is a 1981 Canadian adult animated science fantasy anthology film directed by Gerald Potterton (in his directorial debut) and
produced by Ivan Reitman and Leonard Mogel, who also was the publisher of Heavy Metal magazine, which was the basis for the film.
It starred the voices of Rodger Bumpass, Jackie Burroughs, John Candy, Joe Flaherty, Don Francks, Martin Lavut, Marilyn Lightstone, Eugene Levy,
Alice Playten, Harold Ramis, Percy Rodriguez, Susan Roman, Richard Romanus, August Schellenberg, John Vernon, and Zal Yanovsky.
The screenplay was written by Daniel Goldberg and Len Blum.
The film is an anthology of various science-fiction and fantasy stories tied together
by a single theme of an evil force that is "the sum of all evils".
It was adapted from Heavy Metal magazine and
original stories in the same spirit.
Like the magazine, the film features a great deal of
graphic violence, sexuality, and nudity.
Its production was expedited by having several animation houses
working simultaneously on different segments.
Upon release, the film received mixed reviews from critics, but was a moderate
commercial success and has since achieved a cult following.
Its soundtrack was packaged by music manager Irving Azoff and included several popular rock bands and artists, including Black
Sabbath, Blue Öyster Cult, Sammy Hagar, Don Felder, Cheap Trick, DEVO, Journey, and Nazareth, among others.
A sequel, Heavy Metal 2000, was released in 2000.
The film explores themes of flying car, taxi, heavy
metal, based on comic, drug use.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.